[Music]
so the dugar monster SP is one of our
best of 2023 joining me today to accept
the award is Mr bipple Chandra MD Ducar
India bipp congratul ation thank you
thank you for joining us again and
thanks for calling us time and time so
time and time again you take an award
every year yes are you ever going to
slow down and let other people catch up
no no no not at all why we should so you
know winning Awards and starting the
season with autox is a habit now and we
we love to or we wish to continue with
that well you make incredible bikes and
you make it easy for us to do our jobs
and and fun yes yes that's true so uh
what is it about the monster SP that is
is special well SP we lovingly call this
bike as mad for fun M however just to
put the things in perspective SP is a
moniker which does not come with every
bike and if SP is with a bike then you
can believe that the bike is at the next
level of performance which we talk about
monster SP with so many things like Olin
and tomoni and whatever everything is
there the bike is definitely At a next
level of performance and I'm sure you
would love ride this bike on the road at
the track everywhere so a lovely bike to
ride at all the places so with the
monster and the SC Scrambler two of your
bestselling bikes back in the portfolio
are things looking up for ducatti India
definitely definitely
see uh ducatti portfolio I would say
there are two very clear-cut distinction
one is the uh you can say volume bikes
the likes of scramblers and monsters and
the others you can say are either
performance or
uh in that level kind of bike so with
the V4 engine we have so clearly we have
a V4 and V2 engine and even in V2
scramblers and moners are the number
guzzlers and the balance are you know uh
Next Level kind of bikes so yes the
business is definitely on a high side
the numbers are looking up so that's a
lovely sign for us and how is the Indian
customer changed over the years because
there's been a huge change I mean in
terms of volumes as well and in terms of
the spread of bikes that are available
so how is the customer changed in the
last decade or so well I would say uh
customers are now taking life a bit less
seriously so they are spending time uh
outside the office as well or outside
whatever their work area is so they are
spending time on the road uh giving time
to their passion biking or riding is one
of them so we see lot many new riders
coming into the family which is a very
very good sign for us earlier what used
to happen people were exchanging their
bikes now we find new buyers so that's a
lovely thing to see and uh even some of
the newcomers they are starting with
bikes at V4 level so that's a very very
reassuring thing for us that we are
doing the right thing so things are
looking positive people are traveling
abroad that again gives us a very nice
Advantage because they see these bikes
in various other locations and that
gives them a reason to buy back home
yeah so that's a nice thing so recently
internationally for the first time
you've unveiled your first single
cylinder bike the hypo motad 698 mono uh
when can we see that in India well the
bike will definitely come to India in
due course of time the timeline would be
in next year so we'll come up with the
expected timelines and yes we all are
excited pretty excited that's going to
be a major major fun kind of bike yeah
on the production side there was a
period of time when there were still
production constraints any constraints
still or now it's smooth sailing uh I
would say no constraints now we have uh
put the things in perspective everything
is streamlined in fact uh starting next
year we expect things to go even better
because we shall be starting uh
Productions at our new Factory in
Thailand that that's uh much modern
bigger everything kind of factory so
things will be better only no
constraints no bars as such and Thailand
of course is a great production hub for
you but there's so much talk of making
India any of that anytime in the future
any consideration for assembly or
manufacturer in India well in business
you never say no so at this moment I
cannot say yes or no to this kind of
discussion but uh as business house we
always keep our options open and if
there is a requirement of business why
not so I I do not know or I cannot
comment on the statement today but yes
options will always remain open so Moto
GP just concluded in India for the first
time what was was that experience for
for ducatti India did it yield any
benefit the experience was very good uh
if I can use the word
ethereal which may sound a bit too much
but yes the entire ecosystem was
wonderful the entire process the entire
system worked like a well oiled machine
and there were no issues no hiccups
other than I would say the weather Gods
the temperature was very very high so
other than that it was very very good
and uh for ducatti per se I would say
the experience was amazing very good uh
with the
podiums so now you know it's a matter of
record books that the inaugural Moto GP
Was Won by a Ducati bike so that's
wonderful feeling for us we are very
happy for all our Riders and we look
forward to the next Edition uh I'm sure
uh all the participants including duati
we would have learned from this
experience and we'll try to make the
Moto GP 24 even better experience for
everyone and look looking ahead at at
2024 there seems to be a lot of
geopolitical uncertainty in the world do
you think that will affect bike sales in
India or at your segment things of this
nature won't really have a direct impact
you see at this moment we are not
experiencing any immediate impact you
never know how things
unfold uh God forbid if things come to
your doorstep it would be a different
reality alog together but at this moment
we don't expect anything of that nature
uh I'm sure all the diplomats would be
working in over time and trying to keep
things in the right perspective so I'm
looking towards a brighter future rather
than a Bleaker future so let's hope that
way and 2024 what do you have in store
for us too many things so as you said
hyper mono would be there we have uh 916
anniversario which was unveiled at ikma
very
recently uh at the next Lev level kind
of bike we shall be having some
collaborations with Mari Brands which is
now a Hallmark of ducatti so in fact
very soon if all goes well uh because
production is a different issue we we
might be delivering the street fighter
loggy by the Sim in India so similar
Mari collaboration next year so a lot
many things are planned and uh it would
be in various ranges so if I'm talking
of a Mari brand collaboration at the top
end level then there shall be a multi is
somewhere in between there shall be 916
anniversary at some level so lot many
things would be there good so you're
going to keep us busy once again
extremely busy I would say good and
thank you for making our jobs a lot of
fun and thank you for being here once
again thank you thanks for calling us
congratulations thank
[Music]
you
w